WARNING! The footage you are about to watch is of a sensitive nature
and although it may not be suitable for all viewers, it is for the glory of God.
A shocking condition brought this man to The SCOAN.
His body riddled with a lot of sickness.
Right from the crown of his head, his entire body has been engulfed in a plague,
shattering his skin into scale-like fragments.
There is not a hair left on his head as the frightening sickness has completely destroyed the skin.
From his head, the disease rages across his body, damaging every inch
and rendering his arms useless.
The skin flakes and peels horribly all the way down his arms to his fingers.
Not an inch of his skin has been left unaffected.
This is a body that cannot lie down, bend or work.
A once strong and healthy man - now not even a shadow of his former self
as this debilitating disease has even made menial tasks an unimaginable thought.
Right down his legs to his feet, the storm of destruction continued with no intermission.
Much of the skin has been scratched - here exposing the sensitive flesh.
Some of the broken pieces of his skin can still be seen barely hanging off his hurting body.
His legs are at places as rough as a tree bark; it is uncomfortable and just as disfigured.
Even the small movements he makes to turn must be causing him terrible discomfort.
Demonstrating his fragile state, he touches a piece of his splintered skin which comes off at his hand.
And you can clearly see that more is ready to fall.
Let's listen to him.
My name is Jude Oraka. I come from Anambra State (Nigeria).
I am 39 years old.
Can you please tell us the problem that brought you to The SCOAN today?
I have had skin disease for 6 years.
I cannot sleep; my body itches.
I cannot walk fine; I feel cold.
I have general body pain.
My body used to peel; my skin falls off.
I have gone to hospitals but the doctors don't have any solution.
I have gone to native doctors.
I have taken native medicine but there is no solution.
I am a driver.
Since that time, I can't drive; I stay at home.
So how did you hear about The SCOAN?
I watch Emmanuel TV.
I believe that God will heal me.
We pray with you that God Almighty will set you free
from this problem of terrible skin disease in your life, in Jesus' name.
Amen.
HEALING TIME
Watch your screen. That will help your faith.
Look at the case here.
It is a mysterious issue.
I never knew how he came here
because I don't know the kind of vehicle that would convey this man here.
So let him get free and go.
Man of God, please help my brother; he has skin disease for the past six years.
We have taken him all over; there is no solution.
Neither herbalist homes or hospitals have provided any solution.
Man of God, please help my brother. He has skin disease.
- For how many years?
- For six years, sir.
Ok, let's hear from your brother. What is your problem?
Can you talk?
It is skin disease
Ok, it seems that he cannot talk.
As you see his appearance, so it is on the inside.
Both within and inside is like this.
You will be able to say a word with me?
Are you ready to accept Jesus as your Lord and Saviour?
Yes.
Thank you.
Come on.
I command that disease, that infirmity in your body, in the name of Jesus Christ,
I command that infirmity out! Begin to vomit it out!
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering Prayer In The Power Of The Holy Spirit
Out!
I say, you disease, you can hear me. Come out of this man's life!
In the name of Jesus, come out!
You can see what the name of Jesus can do.
I say, out!
Vomiting Poisonous Substances
I say out, in the name of Jesus Christ!
It must come out because the name of Jesus is given to cast out demons
and to speak to disease.
With the name, we have dominion over all disease, affliction
infirmity, trouble and the challenges in your life.
Vomiting Poisonous Substances
It is poison; he drank poison.
Can you see what I asked you to be patient for?
An issue like this cannot be handled in the same way I handle your case.
Vomiting Poisonous Substances
Look here!
In the name of Jesus, stand up.
Instantly, the man rises to his feet.
He's free.
Before and After
Who is like my Jesus
He is the Alpha and Omega
The Beginning and the End
My Redeemer, my Comforter
Messiah
Everlasting King of Hope
No one is like Jesus
Who is like my Jesus
Who is like my Lord
He is the Alpha Omega
The Beginning and the End
Redeemer Mediator
Comforter Messiah
Everlasting King of Hope
No one is like Him
Who is like my Jesus
He is the Alpha and Omega
The Beginning and the End
My Redeemer, my Comforter
Messiah
Everlasting King of Hope
No one is like Jesus
Who is that your Jesus
Who is that your Lord
God is what He says He is
I don't feel any pain.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
Testimony Time
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So right now, the man is alive and he is here now in our midst.
Please, you are welcome.
Testimony Time
Praise the Lord!
If Jesus Christ could bring Lazarus up from the tomb,
the power and effectiveness are still the same - yesterday, today and forever.
Our brother is a living testimony.
Let us put our hands together beautifully for the King of Glory!
Testimony Time
Please, let us have our seats.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Brethren, Good Morning!
My name is Monica Odey.
The man beside me is my brother, Jude Oraka.
We come from Anambra State (Nigeria).
It all started... He was sick for over six years.
About two years ago, the sickness developed into chronic skin disease.
The disease started gradually but spread from the back to the stomach
to the legs until it affected his entire body, including his head, eyes and ears.
The problem kept getting worse. We took him to hospitals and herbal homes.
We took him everywhere! In short, it became a curse.
If he was coming on the way, people would leave the road.
We didn't have to ask for an excuse; we were already carrying one by our side.
Anywhere they saw us coming, people would start running.
They would ask if it was a ghost or a human being.
I want to thank God today - I didn't know that Jesus was still alive to bring
my brother who was dead back to life today.
We are here to celebrate life and return the glory back to God.
Last year, it was on July 5th that we came here.
When we got to the village, his condition became so terrible.
All of us gathered but nobody could proffer a solution.
They said the problem was beyond human imagination and understanding.
The family discussed what to do about it.
Nobody could offer a solution. At that time, I had just given birth.
I told them that there is only one man that can do this job - Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Okay. Point of correction.
Only God Almighty can do it through His anointed servant Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Remember that the man of God says, I am not the Healer but I know the Healer.
His name is Jesus Christ". All glory be to God!
Let us put our hands together for Jesus!
We realised that there was nothing else to do as we had almost given up hope.
We knew he was a walking corpse, a dead man already
and any money invested on him was wasted as he had no hope of living.
I insisted they allow me to travel to Lagos with him to seek the God of T.B. Joshua.
They then asked me how he could travel from Anambra to Lagos.
They said he may likely die on the road but I said that if that happened,
we would return the corpse back to Makurdi.
I knew if I just stayed and watched him die, I would not be able to forgive myself.
I told them to take a step of faith.
I had a small child with me and they then asked who would travel to Lagos with him.
They said they didn't know about the church activities, so I said I would go.
They asked how I would take the man and my baby, considering his skin disease.
You could not hold him with your bare hands; you had to use a rag to hold him
because his skin was peeling off.
I asked my husband if he would allow me to travel with the child and he agreed.
I said I would go but they said I could not take such a journey alone.
His wife volunteered to go but said she would not be seen with him in public.
I said she should not worry as I was ready to bear the shame.
We took the journey. To dress him up, we put him in four shirts. From up to down.
We gave him thick socks and tied him with a headtie.
We gave him a cap and a pair of spectacles to cover his eyes.
Only the mouth was seen and with that, people were still detecting the problem.
When we got to the bus park, some people saw him and ran away.
I spoke to the driver that God wanted to use him to help us take the man
to The SCOAN in Lagos where God would show forth His mercy.
The driver agreed on the condition that we would stay at the back of the vehicle
so that the other passengers would not get distracted by his infirmity.
I said, "No problem".
We sat at the back but as the vehicle was moving, pieces of his skin were floating
inside the vehicle and it became a problem.
The other passengers became angry with the driver for carrying him,
"Must you collect money by force? Is it every passenger you see that you must carry?"
In short, we faced insults and discrace. Our bodies were smelling.
We kept faith and God brought us from Anambra to The SCOAN; we arrived.
When we were close to The SCOAN, no vehicle would take us to the church. All of them run away.
They said they could not carry such.
When the vehicle dropped us, the driver took a broom
and swept all the pieces of his skin and threw it away.
However, we couldn't find any vehicle to take us to the church in Ikotun.
They said they could not carry a dead man inside their vehicle.
All the taxis rejected us; we stood for about three hours, begging for help.
One driver eventually agreed although he charged double the fare.
I said, "No problem".
He then took us to Ikotun.
Upon reaching there, all the hoteliers ran away and denied their lodges.
Nobody agreed that they had a lodge for him to stay.
Praise God!
Amen.
Ok, for those who don't understand this part:
What the woman is trying to say is that
after all the terrible experience they had, getting to Ikotun where The SCOAN is located...
Coming down from the bus stop, one would usually have those hoteliers
running round you for accommodation, "Please come! No, I'm the first person who got this one!"
"Oya let's go!" They would drag customers.
But when they saw this man, they all ran away.
Amen.
This was not the kind of customer they were looking for.
Ok, continue.
All of them ran away and said they didn't need this type of customer.
We stood at the road for about one hour until we talked to one woman.
She said she would give us an apartment on one condition.
I asked her, "What is the condition?"
- "Double payment."
- I said, "No problem. We will pay".
The woman ushered us to the place.
Even when we entered the lodge, people staying there started running.
We were staying in our own private room but they all ran from the compound.
We give God the glory; the day of the Saturday prayer line came.
We dressed him in a raincoat and covered all of his body
because once you saw his body, you would get scared and not come closer.
Before then, we were going from hospital to hospital.
Could you imagine a sick person in a hospital waiting to see the doctor
who saw another sick patient and ran away for fear of contacting the disease?
Whenever we entered a hospital, all the patients would allow us to go first.
The doctor would have to come out and ask who brought such a patient.
When I said I was the one, he asked how I could do such since I had a little child.
He asked if I had no conscience towards the baby I was carrying.
I said the man in question was my brother and the child was my baby.
I said that I knew nothing would happen to the child.
He told my brother to stay far away from the entrance of the hospital.
He went to sit on a block outside, not even a chair.
They had to take their medical equipment outside to attend to him.
We tried all of this to no avail.
We came back and on that fateful day, as God may have it...
If God says your time has not yet come, no matter how the devil will try,
there will still be a solution.
This young man could not eat; his whole mouth was bruised.
The body had pus all over.
If you sat near him, he would be crying day and night that his body was very hot.
I asked him how we could help him.
He said the only assistance we could give to him was to scratch the body with a broom.
We would carry a small, strong broom and sweep the body.
When did this, he would feel a little bit of relief.
I thank God that when the man of God stretched forth his hand and prayed for him on July 5th,
from that day, he started getting healed.
Today, it has become a history and we are here to say, "Thank You, Jesus!"
Put your hands together for Jesus Christ!
Watch your screen. That will help your faith.
Look at the case here. It is a mysterious issue.
I never knew how he came here
because I don't know the kind of vehicle that would convey this man here.
So let him get free and go.
Man of God, please help my brother; he has skin disease for the past six years.
We have taken him all over; there is no solution.
Neither herbalist homes or hospitals have provided any solution.
Man of God, please help my brother. He has skin disease.
- For how many years?
- For six years, sir.
Ok, let's hear from your brother. What is your problem?
Can you talk?
It is skin disease
Ok, it seems that he cannot talk.
As you see his appearance, so it is on the inside.
Both within and inside is like this.
You will be able to say a word with me?
Are you ready to accept Jesus as your Lord and Saviour?
Yes.
Thank you.
Come on.
I command that disease, that infirmity in your body, in the name of Jesus Christ,
I command that infirmity out! Begin to vomit it out!
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering Prayer In The Power Of The Holy Spirit
Out!
I say, you disease, you can hear me. Come out of this man's life!
In the name of Jesus, come out!
You can see what the name of Jesus can do.
I say, out!
Vomiting Poisonous Substances
I say out, in the name of Jesus Christ!
It must come out because the name of Jesus is given to cast out demons
and to speak to disease.
With the name, we have dominion over all disease, affliction
infirmity, trouble and the challenges in your life.
Vomiting Poisonous Substances
It is poison; he drank poison.
Can you see what I asked you to be patient for?
An issue like this cannot be handled in the same way I handle your case.
Vomiting Poisonous Substances
Look here!
In the name of Jesus, stand up.
Instantly, the man rises to his feet.
He's free.
As you can see, indeed, it has become a history
that he was once suffering from a chronic skin disease.
Looking at the before and after.
Wow, God has done a great thing.
Tell us, all through this period that he was passing through this terrible situation,
was there any hope?
Apart from the time you thought of bringing him here?
We had no hope at all.
Ok.
Now that the Lord, God Almighty has set him free,
you as a sister who had been bearing all the burden, how do you feel?
I feel very happy; if this is the only mission God gave me the grace to accomlish,
I am grateful to Him.
Put your hands together for Jesus Christ!
Indeed, we thank God Almighty for your patience and for being able to stand all this terrible challenge.
And we believe it wasn't you; it was the Spirit of God.
If everyone had deserted him, run away from him,
and you decided to take it upon yourself, even with a month-old baby,
I think it was the Spirit of God.
We also thank God for allowing yourself to be used by the Spirit of God
to bring him to the arena of liberty where he was eventually set free.
Once again, let us clap for Jesus Christ!
Let us hear from the man himself.
Sir, we can't see the smile on your face.
Ok. Now tell us your name.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Jude Oraka. I'm from Anambra State (Nigeria).
The person beside me is my lovely sister.
I want to thank God who used my sister to bring me to The SCOAN.
The problem I had was a chronic skin disease.
Can you just explain to us - because it is said, He who feels it knows it -
what you were experiencing, what was your condition at that time?
How did you feel in your body when you were having this problem?
At that time, I felt heat all over my body.
My body was overheating like a car radiator.
I could not sit down or stand but only lie down.
For 24 hours a day, I was lying down on a bed.
I could not go to the toilet by myself.
I needed assistance in everything I did.
And who was doing that?
My lovely sister was the one helping me.
I was taken to hospitals and also to a herbalist to get native medicine
but it was all in vain.
Everywhere you went, when people saw you, how did they react?
They felt like a masquerade was coming and ran away.
Ok. When you now eventually came to The SCOAN,
the man of God stretched his hand towards you.
Can you describe to us what happened at the prayer line.
When I came and saw the man of God, he asked whether I believed in God.
I said yes.
He then prophesied that it was a poison and I was going to vomit it.
He stretched his hand towards me and I began to shake.
By that time, I was not with myself; I didn't know what was happening.
I vomitted something.
From that time, I started recovering.
And how are you now?
I'm feeling okay.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Ok, we now want you to pull up the sleeves of the cloth you are wearing.
Let us see more of your body.
Also your shoes - let us see the feet that were as rough as the bark of an oak tree then.
But today you can see that it is as smooth as the skin of a bouncing new-born baby.
Wow.
Before and After
For the glory of God, we want to see your feet because we know how it was when you came.
It was terrible looking. One side is okay.
Wow.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Now can you touch, tap, rub it and let us see.
Do you feel anything?
No pain.
Before, when you had this problem, this terrible skin disease,
were you able to touch or rub it?
I could not even bend down.
You couldn't even bend down?
Wow. Can you exercise your body now.
Let us put our hands together for Jesus!
Thank you. Glory be to God in the highest.
Looking at what God has done in your life, setting you free,
bringing you back from death to life,
what word of advice do you have for people who are listening to you?
There are many people out there - doubting Thomases -
who don't even believe in the power of miracle but you are a living testimony.
What advice do you have for them?
What I have to say is that in any situation you face,
don't give up but put your hope in God.
Hallelujah. Thank you very much.
Indeed, no matter the circumstances, no matter the situation, do not lose hope.
Put all your faith and trust in God.
At God's own time, that problem will be over, in Jesus' name.
To God be the glory.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My advice goes like this:
Sometimes, women may have brothers passing through a difficult challenge
in such a way that it is difficult to associate with them.
But if you can summon courage, because even the day he was prayed for,
people who were watching live in Makurdi,
they were calling me to say that I was wicked.
I asked what manner of wickedness I had shown.
They asked why I took such a risk to travel with him and my child to Lagos.
They asked if the man had died on the road, what question would I answer.
I said that even if he died, I was not a murderer but looking for solution.
I knew that God would not allow him to die on the road.
But the risk you take today based on the leading of God will bring success tomorrow.
We are here today celebrating life.
Hallelujah.
Testimony Time
And standing by, watching the man of God just stretching his hand at a distance
towards your brother and he started vomiting, how did you feel?
What can you say about the power of God?
Seeing the man of God alone, even before he stretched his hand to pray,
I knew my brother would not die.
When he stretched forth his hand, I knew the end to the calamity had come.
This is a new beginning!
Hallelujah. Put your hands together for Jesus!
Indeed, a new beginning.
Old things are gone, all things become new.
That is the promise of God.
We want to thank God Almighty for your life, sir.
For being alive today to share this wonderful testimony
because of the grace of God in the life of His able servant Prophet T.B. Joshua.
We also just want to know, because of our viewers all over the world who want to know,
we know that miracle is only a means to an end but not the end itself.
The end is the salvation of our soul.
Can you tell us, since you received this miracle, this healing,
how has it influenced your life? Has it drawn you closer to Christ?
Are you living your life for the glory of God, now that you have received His mercy and grace?
Since I was delivered, I have surrendered my life to Christ.
I will never go back to sin again!
So the way you are talking now with ease,
were you able to talk freely like this with ease, before now?
No.
Hallelujah. No more pain?
There's no more pain. I can talk freely.
Hallelujah. Put your hands together for Jesus!
Thank you. Indeed, this miracle is more than enough to change one's life entirely.
And now that you have recognised the power of God and have also encountered it,
we want to encourage you to remain in faith in Christ Jesus,
continue to make the Word of God the standard for your life
and your miracle will be permanent, in Jesus' name.
Amen.
So once again, sister, we want to thank you very much
for allowing yourself to be used for the glory of God
to bring this man to the arena of liberty where he was set free.
We thank God you are part of this wonderful testimony, in Jesus' name.
Mr Jude Oraka & Sister
Prayerline Testimony
To God be the glory. This is what we are praising God for.
Right now, we are going to call on our choristers to give us wonderful songs of celebration
as we glorify the name of God for this wonderful healing He has done in the life of this man.
Let's rise up to our feet and give glory to God.
At the mention of Your name
Every knee must bow
Every tongue confess
At the mention of Your name
Every knee must bow
Every tongue confess
You are Lord
You are Lord of lords
You are King
You are King of kings
At the mention of Your name
Every knee must bow
Every tongue confess
You are Lord
You are Lord of lords
You are King
You are King of kings
At the mention of Your name
Every knee must bow
Every tongue confess
You are Lord
You are Lord of lords
You are King
You are King of kings
At the mention of Your name
Every knee must bow
Every tongue confess
You want my praises, oh Lord
Testimony Time
Lord, You are so good
Lord, You are kind
Lord, You are so wonderful
My God, You are excellent
Lord, You are so good
Lord, You are kind
Lord, You are so wonderful
My God, You are excellent
Excellent is Your name
Excellent is Your power
Lord, You are so wonderful
My God, You are excellent
Excellent is Your name
Excellent is Your power
Lord, You are so wonderful
My God, You are excellent
Lord, You are so good
Lord, You are kind
Lord, You are wonderful
My God, You are excellent
STANDARD FOR LIFE
We thank God today; we travelled all the way from Makurdi to come and testify.
The man of God sheltered us, gave us accommodation and took care of us.
He fed us with delicious food in the morning, afternoon and evening.
What he has done for us is wonderful and today, we are here to thank Jesus
for all God has used Prophet T.B. Joshua to do in our family.
May the Almighty God reward him, his ministry and his family.
I wish them Heaven at last. They shall make it.
When I had this problem, I couldn't work. My sister helped me to do everything.
She lent me money because I could not work for the past six years.
She gave me money, fed me and helped me in everything that I needed.
I had no money because I couldn't work then.
But now you are back to your work?
I'm back to my work as a driver.
Prophet T.B. Joshua together with Emmanuel TV Partners decided
to give you the total sum of 200,000 naira and also transportation money of 20,000 naira.
Everything is here. The prophet said we should give you this.
Thank You, Jesus! Thank you, Man of God!
I thank you very much for assisting me. I give thanks to God.
I pray God will bless him, his family and the members of Emmanuel TV.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
I am here to appreciate God who used Prophet T.B. Joshua.
He is one among millions; I have never seen someone like him before.
For God to use him to bless my family with the sum of N220,000,
I appreciate him and pray the good Lord would reward him, his family
and all the partners of Emmanuel TV.
His finances shall never run dry and the Lord, my God shall water him.
For the blessing given to this family, it will move from strength to strength,
never backwards. I return all the glory to God. Thank You Jesus!
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today,
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances,
sermons and testimonies from The SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV - Changing lives, Changing nations, and Changing the world.